Guide to the Richard H. Lawrence Photographs, circa 1885-1889 PR 032
New-York Historical Society
Richard H. Lawrence photographs
circa 1885-1889
New-York Historical Society
Lawrence, Richard Hoe
PR 032
1 box(es)
Copy negatives and modern prints of photographs taken by Richard Hoe Lawrence (1858–1936) of the slum conditions on Manhattan's Lower East Side at the end of the 19th century. Social reformer Jacob A. Riis used a number of Lawrence's images in his lectures on "The Other Half." In addition to general street scenes and Coney Island outings, the collection includes views of early baseball games at the Polo Grounds, the aftermath of the Blizzard of 1888, and the celebrations marking the 1889 centennial of George Washington's first inauguration.
Conditions Governing Access
Open to qualified researchers by appointment only. To schedule an appointment, contact the Print Room Librarian at printroom@nyhistory.org.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Copied from lantern slides and albums on loan from the photographer's widow, Mrs. Jessie Cort Lawrence, in 1950.
Arrangement
Prints are filed by subject. Negatives are filed by Society-assigned numbers. The finding aid lists each image by key title subject word and by negative number. Some of the photographs are indexed in the Negative File catalog maintained by the Department of Rights and Reproductions.
Biographical / Historical
Gentleman banker Richard Hoe Lawrence (1858–1936) pursued his antiquarian interests through active participation in the Grolier Club and in the Society of Iconophiles, which published prints illustrating Manhattan's iconography. Lawrence was also an early member of the Society of Amateur Photographers of New York. He produced numerous lantern slides and won a silver prize for hand camera work at the same Society show at which Robert Bracklow and Alfred Stieglitz also won awards.
Related Materials
Other views by Lawrence are found in the Lantern Slide Collection (PR-070). Similar slum images are in the Jacob A. Riis Reference Photograph Collection (PR-059). And the Museum of the City of New York holds several lantern slides credited to Lawrence in its Jacob A. Riis Collection.
Scope and Contents
The collection consists of 202 copy film negatives (black-and-white; 4 x 5 in.) and 189 modern reference prints (black-and-white; 8 x 10 in.). Of special interest are the photographs Richard Hoe Lawrence took for Jacob Riis of slum conditions on Manhattan's Lower East Side in 1887. Lawrence and fellow camera club members Dr. John T. Nagle and Dr. Henry G. Piffard accompanied Riis until Riis learned to photograph on his own. Riis used the resulting lantern slides in his famous lectures on "The Other Half: How It Lives and Dies in New York." Maren Stange has recently shown that Lawrence took at least 31 of the photographs usually credited to Riis, but Lawrence cropped his copies to achieve softer character-type studies. Of the 37 slum views at the Society, five are credited to Piffard, who provided the necessary expertise in lighting dark alleys and interiors with the new magnesium flash powder technique. Other views show opium smokers in Chinatown, homeless lodgers and prisoners at a police station, a "black and tan" dive, and a boys' gang acting out a robbery.
Also significant are eight early action shots of baseball games at the Manhattan Polo Grounds in 1886. More routine views, possibly taken during family or camera club outings, include: beach bathing, the Blizzard of 1888, the 1889 Washington Inaugural Centennial naval and land parades, a fire, the Produce Exchange and Spanish Flats, sport shooting and tennis, house interiors, and Sing Sing prison. Lawrence captioned some of the photographs with descriptive titles and dates. Society staff devised short titles for the others and annotated the slum prints with detailed notes about comparable views by Jacob Riis.
Alleys.; Apartment houses -- New York (State) -- New York.; Baseball.; Blizzards -- New York (State) -- New York.; Fires -- New York (State) -- New York.; Gangs.; Homeless persons -- New York (State) -- New York.; Interiors -- New York (State) -- New York.; Naval parades & ceremonies -- New York (State) -- New York -- 1880-1890.; Opium abuse -- New York (State) -- New York.; Parades -- New York (State) -- New York.; Police stations.; Poor -- New York (State) -- New York.; Prisoners.; Robbery.; Shooting.; Slums -- New York (State) -- New York.; Streets -- New York (State) -- New York.; Tenement houses -- New York (State) -- New York.; Tennis.; negatives (photographs); Photographic prints.; Chinatown (New York, N.Y.); Lower East Side (New York, N.Y.); Spanish Flats (New York, N.Y.); Piffard, Henry G. (Henry Granger), 1842-1910; Riis, Jacob A. (Jacob August), 1849-1914; Washington, George, 1732-1799 -- Anniversaries, etc.; Camera Club of New York; New York Produce Exchange; Polo Grounds (New York, N.Y.); Sing Sing Prison; Society of Amateur Photographers of New York
- Photographic prints
  - 001. Finis! [Police bearing dead man on stretcher] (negative 32300), undated (Offsite-box 1, Folder 1)
  - 002. Robbing a lush (negative 32301), undated (Offsite-box 1, Folder 1)
  - 003. A black and tan Thompson St. dive / "It's frequenters are colored men and white women of the most degraded sort." (negative 32302), undated (Offsite-box 1, Folder 1)
  - 004. New York Tribune Police Bureau opposite Police Headquarters in Mulberry Street, 1879 when two Tribune reporters waited for news to break. Jacob Riis in corner, his partner, Amos Einsign seated at desk. The other man may be the detective from across the street who is at the right hand side in the foundling picture. (negative 32303), undated (Offsite-box 1, Folder 1)
  - 005. [Seated man flanked by two standing. The top border of the photograph cuts off the torsos of those standing. Seated man seen again in photo number 13] (negative 32304), undated (Offsite-box 1, Folder 1)
    General
    Attributed to Dr. Henry G. Piffard.
  - 006. Tramp in Mulberry Street yard (negative 32306), undated (Offsite-box 1, Folder 1)
  - 007. Bandit's Roost at 59 ½ Mulberry St., in the famous Bend (negative 32308), undated (Offsite-box 1, Folder 1)
  - 008. Police Lodging House [male lodgers] (negative 32309), undated (Offsite-box 1, Folder 1)
  - 009. White Slaves / Two Women, mother and daughter / Elizabeth Street (negative 32310), undated (Offsite-box 1, Folder 1)
  - 010. Chinatown Opium Joint (negative 32311), undated (Offsite-box 1, Folder 1)
  - 011. A Chinatown Opium Joint (negative 32312), undated (Offsite-box 1, Folder 2)
  - 012. Waked up by the flash light. The lodging room [for women] in the Thirtieth Street Police Station. (negative 32313), undated (Offsite-box 1, Folder 2)
  - 013. [Group of seven men, one boy. One man is seen again in photo number 5] (negative 32314), undated (Offsite-box 1, Folder 2)
  - 014. [Same image as photo number 13] (negative 32315), undated (Offsite-box 1, Folder 2)
  - 015. Prisoners before police judge / Jacob A. Riis last man at right, facing camera. (negative 32316), undated (Offsite-box 1, Folder 2)
  - 016. Apparently taken by same flash as the companion picture—probably by a second camera operated by Dr. H.G. Piffard / [Arab boarding house, Mott Street] (negative 32317), 1887 (Offsite-box 1, Folder 2)
    Attributed to Dr. Henry G. Piffard. Companion to no. 024 (negative 32326).
  - 017. Girl in Chinese opium joint (negative 32318), undated (Offsite-box 1, Folder 2)
  - 018. Boy asleep under truck (negative 32320), undated (Offsite-box 1, Folder 2)
  - 019. Happy Jack's canvas palace / A Pell St. seven cent lodging house (negative 32321), undated (Offsite-box 1, Folder 2)
  - 020. Police Station Lodger [man asleep] (negative 32322), undated (Offsite-box 1, Folder 2)
  - 021. [Five mustached men (four in police uniforms) at desk] (negative 32323), undated (Offsite-box 1, Folder 3)
  - 022. [Man in fur-trimmed coat being rushed into jail cell by officer] (negative 32324), undated (Offsite-box 1, Folder 3)
  - 023. Chinese opium joint, Mott St. (negative 32325), undated (Offsite-box 1, Folder 3)
  - 024. Interior of an Arab boarding house. Washington Street, New York (negative 32326), 1887 (Offsite-box 1, Folder 3)
  - 025. East Side Oyster House (negative 32327), undated (Offsite-box 1, Folder 3)
  - 026. A Thompson St. "Black and Tan Dive" (negative 32328), undated (Offsite-box 1, Folder 3)
  - 027. The Tombs / "Murderers Row" [Hallway of jail cells] (negative 32329), undated (Offsite-box 1, Folder 3)
  - 028. "Bringing a foundling to Police Headquarters" (negative 32330), undated (Offsite-box 1, Folder 3)
  - 029. Looking west on 29th Street from Madison Avenue, after the Blizzard of 1888 (negative 32331) (Offsite-box 1, Folder 3)
  - 030. Gotham Court / 38 Cherry Street / Double and single alley (negative 32332), undated (Offsite-box 1, Folder 3)
  - 031. [High snow drifts in street] (negative 32333), [1888] (Offsite-box 1, Folder 4)
  - 032. Mulberry Street? Jail yard (negative 32334), undated (Offsite-box 1, Folder 4)
  - 033. A Thompson Street "Black and Tan Dive" (negative 32335), undated (Offsite-box 1, Folder 4)
  - 034. Morgue [interior view] (negative 32336), undated (Offsite-box 1, Folder 4)
  - 035. East side cheam lodging house [interior of, with sleeping lodgers] (negative 32337), undated (Offsite-box 1, Folder 4)
  - 036. Statue of George Washington / Sub. Treasury Wall St. at Nassau St. (negative 32339), 1888 (Offsite-box 1, Folder 4)
  - 037. Liberty Street East from a point west o f William Street (negative 32341), 1888 (Offsite-box 1, Folder 4)
  - 038. Blizzard of March 12, 1888 [Horse and carriage in street] (negative 32342) (Offsite-box 1, Folder 4)
  - 039. [Opulent parlor interior] (negative 32351), undated (Offsite-box 1, Folder 4)
  - 040. [Dirt street; brick shop & hotel fronts, work horses] (negative 32350), undated (Offsite-box 1, Folder 4)
  - 041. [Wooden two story pavilion; group playing in sand in foreground; ocean not visible (Coney Island)] (negative 32353), undated (Offsite-box 1, Folder 5)
  - 042. [Heavily populated pier and beach scene (Coney Island)] (negative 32354), undated (Offsite-box 1, Folder 5)
  - 043. [Elephantine Colossus, Coney Island] (negative 32355), circa 1885 (Offsite-box 1, Folder 5)
  - 044. [Busy beach side pavilion; restaurant and public area (Coney Island)] (negative 32356), undated (Offsite-box 1, Folder 5)
  - 045. [Boat: the Nassau; bare horizon in background] (negative 32357), undated (Offsite-box 1, Folder 5)
  - 046. [Gravesite of St. Clair Pollock, 1797, aged 5 years; on Riverside Drive] (negative 32359), undated (Offsite-box 1, Folder 5)
  - 047. [Memorial to the Seventh Regiment of the Union Army, 1861–1865] (negative 32360), undated (Offsite-box 1, Folder 5)
  - 048. [Statue of Liberty; ships in foreground] (negative 32361), undated (Offsite-box 1, Folder 5)
  - 049. [Statue of Liberty] (negative 32362), undated (Offsite-box 1, Folder 5)
  - 050. [Greek Revival Mansion] (negative 32364), undated (Offsite-box 1, Folder 5)
  - 051. [Sunnyside, home of Washington Irving] (negative 32364), undated (Offsite-box 1, Folder 6)
  - 052. [Sunnyside, home of Washington Irving] (negative 32366), undated (Offsite-box 1, Folder 6)
  - 053. "The Rogues Gallery" / Police Headquarters (negative 32367), undated (Offsite-box 1, Folder 6)
  - 054. [Centennial of 1889, New York City; crowd] (negative 32372) (Offsite-box 1, Folder 6)
  - 055. [Centennial of 1889, New York City; parade; Hinney Bros. horse-drawn float] (negative 32373) (Offsite-box 1, Folder 6)
  - 056. [Centennial of 1889, New York City; parade; military demonstration] (negative 32374) (Offsite-box 1, Folder 6)
  - 057. [Centennial of 1889, New York City; parade; horse-drawn floats, crowd] (negative 32375) (Offsite-box 1, Folder 6)
  - 058. [Centennial of 1889, New York City; parade; Hinney Bros. horse-drawn float] (negative 32376) (Offsite-box 1, Folder 6)
  - 059. Centennial of 1889 / New York City (negative 32377) (Offsite-box 1, Folder 6)
  - 060. [Centennial of 1889, New York City; parade; men on horses] (negative 32378) (Offsite-box 1, Folder 6)
  - 061. [Centennial of 1889, New York City; parade; floats] (negative 32379) (Offsite-box 1, Folder 7)
  - 062. [Centennial of 1889, New York City; festive boats in the East River, near the Brooklyn Bridge] (negative 32403) (Offsite-box 1, Folder 7)
  - 063. [Beneath the pier at the beach (Coney Island)] (negative 32409), undated (Offsite-box 1, Folder 7)
  - 064. [People playing at the beach (Coney Island)] (negative 32410) [Note: same pier as no. 42], undated (Offsite-box 1, Folder 7)
  - 065. [Bathing pavilion, ocean (Coney Island)] (negative 32411), undated (Offsite-box 1, Folder 7)
  - 066. [Children playing at beach (Coney Island)] (negative 32412), undated (Offsite-box 1, Folder 7)
  - 067. [Adults at the beach (Coney Island)] (negative 32413), undated (Offsite-box 1, Folder 7)
  - 068. Coney Island [woman on beach with sailboats] (negative 32414), [1889] (Offsite-box 1, Folder 7)
  - 069. [Adults at the beach (Coney Island)] (negative 32416), undated (Offsite-box 1, Folder 7)
  - 070. [Children at the beach (Coney Island)] (negative 32417), undated (Offsite-box 1, Folder 7)
  - 071. [Seven adults posing in front of sailboat, ocean] (negative 32418), undated (Offsite-box 1, Folder 8)
  - 072. [Four adults playing in marshy ocean] (negative 32419), undated (Offsite-box 1, Folder 8)
  - 073. [Six adults playing in marshy ocean] (negative 32420), undated (Offsite-box 1, Folder 8)
  - 074. Sing Sing [village] (negative 32428), 1886 (Offsite-box 1, Folder 8)
  - 075. Barge Office 480 (negative 32429), 1886 (Offsite-box 1, Folder 8)
  - 076. [Brick mansion, street view] (negative 32430), 1886 (Offsite-box 1, Folder 8)
  - 077. [Clapboard barn, outbuildings along marshy stream; near 138th Street and 5th Avenue] (negative 32431), 1886 (Offsite-box 1, Folder 8)
  - 078. Near 137th St. and Madison Avenue (negative 32432), 1886 (Offsite-box 1, Folder 8)
  - 079. [Clapboard "News Depot" along dirt road] (negative 32433), 1886 (Offsite-box 1, Folder 8)
  - 080. Near 138th St. and 5th Ave. [Clapboard barn, outbuildings, horse along marshy stream] (negative 32434), 1886 (Offsite-box 1, Folder 8)
  - 081. [Opulent parlor interior] (negative 32435), 1886 (Offsite-box 1, Folder 9)
  - 082. Sing Sing [village] (negative 32436), 1886 (Offsite-box 1, Folder 9)
  - 083. Near 137th St. and Madison Ave., N.Y.C. [farmyard, goats] (negative 32437), [1886] (Offsite-box 1, Folder 9)
  - 084. 500 yard [shooting] range (negative 32438), 1886 (Offsite-box 1, Folder 9)
  - 085. [Horse and buggy with driver; rural scene] (negative 32439), undated (Offsite-box 1, Folder 9)
  - 086. Park Ave. [in winter] (negative 32440), 1886 (Offsite-box 1, Folder 9)
  - 087. [Women singing a duet at the piano] (negative 32411), 1886 (Offsite-box 1, Folder 9)
  - 088. [View of mansion from horse-drawn work cart] (negative 32442), 1886 (Offsite-box 1, Folder 9)
  - 089. [View from park of New York's City Hall] (negative 32443), 1886 (Offsite-box 1, Folder 9)
  - 090. [View from park of a (cathedral)] (negative 32445), 1886 (Offsite-box 1, Folder 9)
  - 091. [31 East 33rd Street] (negative 32446), undated (Offsite-box 1, Folder 10)
  - 092. [Street construction] (negative 32447), undated (Offsite-box 1, Folder 10)
  - 093. [George Washington Memorial on Wall Street] (negative 32448), undated (Offsite-box 1, Folder 10)
  - 094. [Pedestrians in wide intersection] (negative 32449), undated (Offsite-box 1, Folder 10)
  - 095. 101st Street between 3rd and Lexington Ave. (negative 32450), 1886 (Offsite-box 1, Folder 10)
  - 096. [View from a high window of a wide boulevard and a low city skyline] (negative 325451), undated (Offsite-box 1, Folder 10)
  - 097. [Woman in a horse-drawn cab] (negative 32452), undated (Offsite-box 1, Folder 10)
  - 098. [Street view: many bicycles, one coach, rail tracks, brick buildings] (negative 32453), undated (Offsite-box 1, Folder 10)
  - 099. [Winter view from a high window of a wide boulevard and a low city skyline] (negative 32454), undated (Offsite-box 1, Folder 10)
  - 100. [Late winter view of cobblestone street, mansions] (negative 32455), 1886 (Offsite-box 1, Folder 10)
  - 101. [Same images as nos. 80 & 102: Near 138th St. and 5th Ave.] (negative 32456), [1886] (Offsite-box 1, Folder 11)
  - 102. Near 138th St. and 5th Avenue [same image as nos. 80 & 101] (negative 32456), [1886] (Offsite-box 1, Folder 11)
  - 103. Broad Street, New York / Mills Building and US Sub-Treasury (negative 32457), undated (Offsite-box 1, Folder 11)
  - 104. [Mansion] (negative 32459), 1886 (Offsite-box 1, Folder 11)
  - 105. Sing Sing 659 [prison; construction] (negative 32466), 1886 (Offsite-box 1, Folder 11)
  - 106. [Work horses near dirt yard; urban setting] (negative 32462), 1886 (Offsite-box 1, Folder 11)
  - 107. [Clapboard mansion] (negative 32463), 1886 (Offsite-box 1, Folder 11)
  - 108. [Train approaching station; rural setting] (negative 32464), 1886 (Offsite-box 1, Folder 11)
  - 109. Hastings [woman on tracks of rail yard] (negative 32465), 1886 (Offsite-box 1, Folder 11)
  - 110. Sing Sing 656 [village; municipal building] (negative 32466), 1886 (Offsite-box 1, Folder 11)
  - 111. Sing Sing [village; children playing among clapboard houses] (negative 32467), 1886 (Offsite-box 1, Folder 12)
  - 112. Temporary Mill / M.S. Hart (negative 32468), 1886 (Offsite-box 1, Folder 12)
  - 113. [Nurse with little girl, pram; rural setting] (negative 32469), 1886 (Offsite-box 1, Folder 12)
  - 114. Spanish Flats / 59th St. (negative 32470), 1886 (Offsite-box 1, Folder 12)
  - 115. The Spanish Flats / 150 to 180 West 59th St. to Seventh Avenue (negative 32471), 1886 (Offsite-box 1, Folder 12)
  - 116. [Coaches and horses on wide, rural, dirt road] (negative 32472), 1886 (Offsite-box 1, Folder 12)
  - 117. [Coaches and horses on wide, rural, dirt road] (negative 32473), 1886 (Offsite-box 1, Folder 12)
  - 118. [Large brick building with clock tower] (negative 32474), 1886 (Offsite-box 1, Folder 12)
  - 119. [Opulent parlor interiors] (negative 32475), 1886 (Offsite-box 1, Folder 12)
  - 120. [Opulent parlor interior] (negative 32476), 1886 (Offsite-box 1, Folder 12)
  - 121. [Same image as no. 120] (negative 32476), [1886] (Offsite-box 1, Folder 13)
  - 122. [Wealthy parlor window; different view, same parlor as nos. 120 & 121] (negative 32477), 1886 (Offsite-box 1, Folder 13)
  - 123. [Home library interior] (negative 32478), 1886 (Offsite-box 1, Folder 13)
  - 124. Boston at New York [Baseball game] (negative 32484), 1886 (Offsite-box 1, Folder 13)
  - 125. R.L. Major Perving [playing tennis] (negative 32486), undated (Offsite-box 1, Folder 13)
  - 126. [At tennis] (negative 32487), undated (Offsite-box 1, Folder 13)
  - 127. [At tennis] (negative 32488), undated (Offsite-box 1, Folder 13)
  - 128. Erie Grain Elevator (negative 32489), undated (Offsite-box 1, Folder 13)
  - 129. Coenties Slip (negative 32490), 1886 (Offsite-box 1, Folder 14 [or 13?])
  - 130. [Looking across a river from a set of piers; tug boat] (negative 32491), 1886 (Offsite-box 1, Folder 14 [or 13?])
  - 131. Steamship / Egyptian Monarch (negative 32493), 1886 (Offsite-box 1, Folder 14)
  - 132. Sing Sing [prison] (negative 32495), 1886 (Offsite-box 1, Folder 14)
  - 133. Sing Sing [prison] (negative 32496), [1886] (Offsite-box 1, Folder 14)
  - 134. Sing Sing [prison] (negative 32497), 1886 (Offsite-box 1, Folder 14)
  - 135. Jumel Mansion (negative 32498), 1886 (Offsite-box 1, Folder 14)
  - 136. Lawrence Family (negative 32499), 1886 (Offsite-box 1, Folder 14)
  - 137. Eliphalet Wood residence / Irving Cliff / Irving, N.Y. / Henry Dudley archt. / Built 1868–1869 (negative 32500), undated (Offsite-box 1, Folder 14)
  - 138. Richard Hoe Lawrence (negative 32501), 1886 (Offsite-box 1, Folder 14)
  - 139. Hudson River [from a dock] (negative 32502), undated (Offsite-box 1, Folder 14)
  - 140. [Dirty riverside road lined with brick buildings] (negative 32503), undated (Offsite-box 1, Folder 14)
  - 141. [Shipyard] (negative 32504), undated (Offsite-box 1, Folder 15)
  - 142. [Empty shipyard, from water looking to land] (negative 32505), 1886 (Offsite-box 1, Folder 15)
  - 143. Fulton Ferry (negative 32506), 1886 (Offsite-box 1, Folder 15)
  - 144. Erie Grain Elevator / Jersey City, N.J. (negative 32507), 1886 (Offsite-box 1, Folder 15)
  - 145. [Three men in hunting garb, posing together in field] (negative 32509), undated (Offsite-box 1, Folder 15)
  - 146. 200 yard [shooting] range / Creedmoor (negative 32510), undated (Offsite-box 1, Folder 15)
  - 147. Taluradge, Landon, Williamson, Richard and LeDeus [at] Creedmoor (negative 32511), undated (Offsite-box 1, Folder 15)
  - 148. Wall St. (negative 32512), undated (Offsite-box 1, Folder 15)
  - 149. Tug Rampo (negative 32513), 1886 (Offsite-box 1, Folder 15)
  - 150. [Stone lighthouse at water's edge] (negative 32514), 1886 (Offsite-box 1, Folder 15)
  - 151. [Cougar statue in park] (negative 32515), 1886 (Offsite-box 1, Folder 16)
  - 152. [Workhorses pulling heavy load; rural scene] (negative 32516), 1886 (Offsite-box 1, Folder 16)
  - 153. Sleepy Hollow [Washington Irving's grave] (negative 32518), 1886 (Offsite-box 1, Folder 16)
  - 154. Camel yard / 1886 / Central Park Zoo / Note white turkey / earliest known view / Aspen New York Zoological Park (negative 35219) (Offsite-box 1, Folder 16)
  - 155. Veteran's Room Seventh Regiment Armory (negative 69099), undated (Offsite-box 1, Folder 16)
  - 156. Pottier & Stymus fire / 42 St. & Lex. Ave., undated (Offsite-box 1, Folder 16)
  - 157. [Shooting at the range], undated (Offsite-box 1, Folder 16)
  - 158. Park Ave & 39 St. [after blizzard], 1888 (Offsite-box 1, Folder 16)
  - 159. [Shooting at the range], undated (Offsite-box 1, Folder 16)
  - 160. Trinity Church, 1888 (Offsite-box 1, Folder 16)
  - 161. [Five women singing from (hymnals)], undated (Offsite-box 1, Folder 17)
  - 162. Fire, Pottier & Stymus / 42 St. & Lex. Ave., undated (Offsite-box 1, Folder 17)
  - 163. Pottier & Stymus fire / 42 St. & Lex. Ave., undated (Offsite-box 1, Folder 17)
  - 164. [Pictorial view of wide, rural stream with clapboard house half hidden], undated (Offsite-box 1, Folder 17)
  - 165. [Pictorial view of wooden house with window opening to wide, rural stream], undated (Offsite-box 1, Folder 17)
  - 166. Central Park [central fountain], undated (Offsite-box 1, Folder 17)
  - 167. High Bridge—Aqueduct, undated (Offsite-box 1, Folder 17)
  - 168. "Retreat" / Seventh Regiment National Guard of the State of New York / encampment at Peekskill, undated (Offsite-box 1, Folder 17)
  - 169. Central Park [in winter, on ice], undated (Offsite-box 1, Folder 17)
  - 170. [West Brighton Museum (Coney Island)], undated (Offsite-box 1, Folder 17)
  - 171. Cornfield, undated (Offsite-box 1, Folder 18)
  - 172. [At the beach (Coney Island)], undated (Offsite-box 1, Folder 18)
  - 173. Lady with parasol, undated (Offsite-box 1, Folder 18)
  - 174. Children and nurse, undated (Offsite-box 1, Folder 18)
  - 175. "On the Saw Mill River, Westchester Co., N.Y.", undated (Offsite-box 1, Folder 18)
  - 176. Volunteer & Thistle race, 1889 (Offsite-box 1, Folder 18)
  - 177. Volunteer & Thistle race, 1889 (Offsite-box 1, Folder 18)
  - 178. Volunteer & Thistle race, 1889 (Offsite-box 1, Folder 18)
  - 179. The Thistle / Race between the Volunteer and the Thistle, 1889 (Offsite-box 1, Folder 18)
  - 180. Castle Garden / Emigrants in foreground, undated (Offsite-box 1, Folder 18)
  - 181. The Saw Mill River, Westchester Co., N.Y., undated (Offsite-box 1, Folder 19)
  - 182. New York City (??) rooftops, undated (Offsite-box 1, Folder 19)
  - 183. "Portico" / Near Sleepy Hollow, undated (Offsite-box 1, Folder 19)